# **SAGRA MIELGO**

sagramielgo@gmail.com +34 606712622

## **My Portfolio**

### **EDUCATION**

- 2020-2021 Front-End and web development program.
   Digital school for women Adalab.
- 2018 Speech therapy and Phoniatrics.
  Intensive course. DELENA school.
- 2014 Language science and y Hispanic linguistics. UNED University.
- 2011-2013 Speaker and voiceover actress.
   AM school.
- **2001 ENG-Philology**Deusto University.

## TECHNICAL SKILLS JR FRONT-END DEVELOPER

- Layout: HTML5, CSS3, SASS Flex-box, Grid.
- Responsive design, mobile first.
- JavaScript (ES6), SPAs with React,
- Web services, API rest.
- Node js, Express js.
- Version control with Git.
- Data base: SOL, SOLite
- Tools: **VSCode**, Postman, **Github**, Slack, Zeplin,
- Remote work, LiveShare.

#### **MORE**

- Frame work Agile y SCRUM
- Video edition. Camtassia Profesional.
- Planning, organization and task coordination for presentations and corporate events .
- Radio technician. Digital and analog studio tools.

## **PROJECTS**

- Characters finder. API rest, React, Grid, animations.
- <u>Tv series finder</u>. JavaScript, Flex-box.
- **React Magicians.** Refactorize to React a JavaScript inherited code. Node js, Express js, servers y database SQLite.
- DevRockets. Layout HTML5, SASS, responsive mobile-first.
- Poke-SPA. Simple and dynamic design. React.
- Random Number Game. SPA JavaScript.
- This is me. Virtual profile cards generator, Javascript.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## TV HOSTING, COMMUNICATION AND VOCAL COACHING

- 2021 Communication coach. Leadership and Technologies center.
   UPM (Polytechnic University of Madrid).
- 1998-2021 Copywriter, speaker, presenter radio & tv. Tel5, Ant3, Cuatro, EITB, Canal Extremadura.
- 1995-2021 Actress, singer y musical theatre artist.
- SEO writer. Freelance.
- **Coordinator and host: <u>events</u>** and conferences. Fundación Reina Sofía, Huawei,
- **Proofreader**, Spanish texts & screenwriter,
- Presenter and speaker, Online courses, e-learning.
- Teaching: Spanish language and literature. <u>Music</u> and singing.
   Vocal Coach & Enterprise communication expert.
- Video producer and editor.
- Theatre manager, assistant director, extras and stunts coordinator.
   Cinema & tv.











## **ABOUT ME**

I always wanted to be a singer, a teacher and an astronaut. With effort and dedication I studied **Philology**, singing, music and theatre; my professional experience has been linked to music, **communication**, tv and radio.

I have travelled **around the world**, I have worked in Japan, Argentina, UK and different Spanish cities. I am an inquisitive person, cultural **diversity lover** and passionate about comparative linguistics.

I am self-taught in editing my own audio-visual material, my computer has been my travel partner.

I am tenacious and **committed**, and a disciplined sports person. All these experiences helped me develop technical and **managerial skills**, such as: adaptability and **empathy** to understand the needs of each project. I overcame adversities with other people's help, that is why, at work and in my personal life, I believe in **team work**. I am taking off as a front-end developer with **enthusiasm**. Houston, the countdown is starting.

## **LANGUAGES**

- ES Native.
- ENG B2-C1.
- CAT (Valenciano) Professional.
- Barely: Japanese, German & Euskera.

## **SOFT SKILLS**

Teamwork, active listening.
Effective communication, empathy and adaptability.
Creativity and resolution.
Good work ethic and responsible.
Self-motivating and proactive.

Organization, public speaking and management skills.

## **VOLUNTEERING**

Music teacher La Ciudad de los Muchachos 2017-2019

Guide dogs trainer <u>ONCE</u> 2004-2015 Social rehabilitation of female prisoners <u>ACOPE</u> 2005-2009

## **INTERESTED IN...**

Marathon runner.

Piano & guitar. Jazz standards, Real Book. Hospitality assistant, really good cook. Theatre and cinema make-up artist.